Guide to the Sam di Bonaventura papers, 1900-1998
George Mason University Libraries
- Dr. Sam di Bonaventura papers
  - folder title (Box 139)
    Contents: Medieval II 1967-68 39 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, photocopied book chapters, and musical examples for a course in medieval music. Date(s) of materials: ? Medieval IX 1970-1973 39 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for courses in medieval music. Date(s) of materials: 1970-1973. Medieval Music/ Music Appreciation 39 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture outlines and photocopied book chapters for courses in medieval music and in music appreciation. Date(s) of materials: ? Medieval VI 1969-1974 39 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture outlines and photocopied scores for courses in medieval music as well as research and lecture material on Japanese music. Date(s) of materials: 1969-1970. Medieval VII 1973-1974 39 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book chapters for a course in medieval music. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1974.
  - Medieval, Misc,. Monet, Monteverdi, Mozart (Box 140)
    Contents: Medieval VIII 1973-1974 40 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, and photocopied or dittoed scores for a course in medieval music. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1974. Misc. 1991 40 1 item Contents: binder contains documentation of Di Bonaventura's university and professional activities and responsibilities, including committee/panel assignments, memberships, courses taught, lectures, writings of program notes, honors and awards, etc. Date(s) of materials: 1991. Monet 40 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards which reproduce paintings by Claude Monet (1840-1926. Date(s) of materials: ? Monteverdi (Course) 1974-1975 40 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes and outlines, and photocopied scores for courses in the sacred music of Claudio Monteverdi (1567-1643). Date(s) of materials: 1974-1975. Mozart 40 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards and clippings depicting images of Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (1756-1791) and of buildings where he lived and worked. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Music 531, Music and Nature, Music Halls, Music History, Musical Style, National Wildlife, International Wildlife (Box 141)
    Contents: Music 531 20th C. 1995 41 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, photocopied book excerpts, and photocopied scores for a course in 20th-century music. Date(s) of materials: 1995. Music and Nature 1992 41 1 item Contents: binder contains notes and photocopied scores for a lecture series on "Music and Nature." Date(s) of materials: 1992. Music Halls 41 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards showing various concert halls. Date(s) of materials: ? Music History II 1984-1991 41 1 item Contents: binder contains examinations given in courses in music history. Date(s) of materials: 1984-1991. Musical Style 41 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture outlines, notes, and photocopied scores for a course in the history of musical style. Date(s) of materials: ? National Wildlife 1973-1976 41 1 item Contents: binder contains several issues of the magazine National Wildlife. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1976. International Wildlife 1973-1976 41 1 item Contents: binder contains several issues of the magazine International Wildlife. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1976.
  - Nationalism, Nature, Opera (Box 142)
    Contents: Nationalism I 1968 42 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in musical Nationalism. Date(s) of materials: 1968. Nationalism II 42 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied materials for a course in musical Nationalism. Date(s) of materials: ? Nature 42 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts and photocopied album liner notes for a course in Music and Nature. Date(s) of materials: ? Opera I 1968-1973 42 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes and outlines, and photocopied materials for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1968-1973. Opera II 1972 42 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, photocopied book chapters, and photocopied scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1972.
  - Opera (Box 143)
    Contents: Opera III 1972 43 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts and scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1972. Opera IV 1972 43 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts and scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1972. Opera V 1972 43 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts and scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1972. Opera VI 1972 43 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts and scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1972.
  - Opera (Box 144)
    Contents: Opera VII 1968 44 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1968. Opera VIII 1968 44 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1968. Opera IX 1968-1973 44 1 item Contents: binder contains copies of student term papers and an examination related to courses in the history of opera. Date(s) of materials: 1968-1973. Oral Reports 1988-1995 44 1 item Contents: binder contains primarily outlines and scripts for oral reports by students on terms and topics from music history. Date(s) of materials: 1988-1995.
  - 1985-1991, PAGE, Paintings, Peabody Conservatory (Box 145)
    Contents: 1985-1991 45 1 item Contents: binder containing syllabi, notes, lecture outlines, photocopied book excerpts, assignments, etc. for PAGE 122, an interdisciplinary course in the appreciation of literature, music, and art. Date(s) of materials: 1985-1991. PAGE (2) 45 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture outlines, notes, and photocopied materials for PAGE 122, an interdisciplinary course in the appreciation of literature, music, and art. Date(s) of materials: ? PAGE Quiz 1985-1990 45` 1 item Contents: binder containing tests used in PAGE 122, an interdisciplinary course in the appreciation of literature, music, and art. Date(s) of materials: 1985-1990. Paintings 45 1 item Contents: binder containing color clippings and postcards reproducing paintings by various artists. Date(s) of materials: ? Peabody Conservatory 1964-1967 45 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, assignments, dictation exercises, etc. for courses in symphonic literature and basic music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1964-1967.
  - Personal, Pointillism (Box 146)
    Contents: Personal I 1955-1979 46 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied newspaper, magazine, and program clippings and publicity materials about Ann di Bonaventura Flaccavento (violinist and conductor), Anthony di Bonaventura (pianist), and Mario di Bonaventura (conductor). Date(s) of materials: 1955-1979. Personal II 1970-1975 46 1 item Contents: binder contains professional correspondence, applications for university positions, meeting minutes, photocopied clippings, etc. Date(s) of materials: 1970-1975. Personal III 1967-1982 46 1 item Contents: binder contains correspondence and ephemeral materials related to Dr. di Bonaventura's associations with Peabody Conservatory, George Mason University, ASCAP, Yale, Harvard, the Smithsonian Institution, the Music Critics Association, etc. Date(s) of materials: 1967-1982. Pointillism 46 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards and clippings reproducing works of pointillistic art. Date(s) of materials: 1991? [unlabeled] 46 1 item Contents: binder contains postcards depicting Liszt, Tchaikovsky, and Verdi. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Professional, Misc., Renaissance (Box 147)
    Contents: Professional Misc. 1990-1991 47 1 item Contents: binder containing summaries of academic responsibilities and commitments, community service, creative projects, professional affiliations, etc. related to annual faculty evaluation. Date(s) of materials: 1990-1991. Renaissance I 1970 47 1 item Contents: binder containing primarily copies of students' term-papers for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1970. Renaissance II 1974 47 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1974. Renaissance III 1974 47 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1974.
  - Renaissance (Box 148)
    Contents: Renaissance 4 48 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: ? Renaissance I 1965 1964-1974 48 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture outlines and student grades for courses in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1964-1974. Renaissance II Summer 67 1974 48 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1974. Renaissance III 1972-1974 48 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts, and photocopied scores for courses in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1972-1974.
  - Renaissance, Reviews (Box 149)
    Contents: Renaissance IV Summer 67 1974 49 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1974. Renaissance V 1968 49 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: ? Reviews 1965-1980 49 1 item Contents: binder containing photocopied clippings of concert reviews written by Sam di Bonaventura and published in Baltimore Sun. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1980. Reviews III 1972-1975 49 1 item Contents: binder containing primarily typescripts and photocopied clippings of concert reviews written by di Bonaventura for the Baltimore Sun, and related materials. Date(s) of materials: 1972-1975.
  - Ricercar Canzona, Romantic (Box #)
    Contents: Ricercar Canzona I 1975 50 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in Renaissance music, particularly the genres of canzona, chanson, and ricercar. Date(s) of materials: 1975. Ric[ercar] Canz[ona] II 1975 50 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and similar materials for a course in Renaissance music, particularly the genre of ricercar. Date(s) of materials: 1975. Romantic (1) 1983 50 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts, etc. for Music 535, a course in musical Romanticism. Date(s) of materials: 1983. Romantic II 50 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts, etc. for a course in musical Romanticism. Date(s) of materials: ? Romantic III 1988-1990 50 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts for courses introducing music history. Date(s) of materials: 1988-1990.
  - Schonbrunn, S di B (profesional) (Box 151)
    Contents: Schonbrun[n] 51 1 item Contents: binder containing color postcards and clippings of the Schonbrunn Palace in Vienna. Date(s) of materials: ? S di B 1993 1993 51 1 item Contents: binder containing summaries of academic responsibilities and commitments, community service, creative projects, professional affiliations, etc. related to annual faculty evaluation. Date(s) of materials: 1993 S di B 1992 1992 51 1 item Contents: binder containing summaries of academic responsibilities and commitments, community service, creative projects, professional affiliations, etc. related to annual faculty evaluation. Date(s) of materials: 1992. S di B I 1975-1985 51 1 item Contents: binder containing annual summaries of academic activities with supporting documents. Date(s) of materials: 1975-1985. S di B II 1976-1985 51 1 item Contents: binder containing primarily photocopied of concert reviews and program notes written by di Bonaventura. Date(s) of materials: 1976-1985.
  - Sonata, Spanish Art, Survey (Box 152)
    Contents: Sonata I 1974-1975 52 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied scores, and student grades for a course in the Baroque sonata. Date(s) of materials: 1974-1975. Sonata II 1974-1975 52 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in the Baroque sonata. Date(s) of materials: 1974-1975. Spanish Art 52 1 item Contents: binder containing color postcards and clippings reproducing artwork by Spanish painters. Date(s) of materials: ? Survey 1 1979-1994 52 1 item Contents: binder containing syllabi, lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied materials for Music 231, Survey of World Music. Date(s) of materials: 1979-1994. Survey 2 52 1 item Contents: binder containing lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts, and photocopied scores for a course in world music as well as miscellaneous lecture notes. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Survey, Symphonic Lit. (Box 153)
    Contents: Survey 3 1986-1990 53 1 item Contents: binder contains student reports, lecture notes, and photocopied materials related to courses in world music Date(s) of materials: 1986-1990. Symphonic Lit I 1966-1974 53 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1966-1974. Symphonic Lit II 1973-1974 53 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1974. Symphonic Lit III 1966 53 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1966.
  - Symphonic Lit. [Literature] (Box 154)
    Contents: Symphonic Lit IV 1973-1974 54 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1974. Symphonic Literature 1966-67 I 1964-1969 54 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied materials for courses in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1964-1969. Symphonic Literature 1966-67 II 54 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied scores, and photocopied book excerpts for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: ? Symphonic Literature 1966-67 III 1966 54 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1966.
  - Symphonic Literature, Tchaikowski, Test Material, Theory (Box 155)
    Contents: Symphonic Literature 1966-67 IV 1966-1967 55 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1966-1967. Symphonic Literature V 1973-1974 55 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in symphonic literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973-1974. Tchaikowsky 55 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied book excerpts for a course in the music of Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky (1840-1893). Date(s) of materials: ? Test Material 55 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied tests from Study Guide for The Enjoyment of Music by Bergreen and Castellini. Date(s) of materials: 1963? Theory 1965-1968 55 1 item Contents: binder contains exercises and tests for courses in music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1968. Theory 1965-1967 55 1 item Contents: binder contains primarily lecture notes, musical examples, and exercises for courses in beginning and intermediate harmony. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1967.
  - Theory (Box 156)
    Contents: Theory 1961-1962 56 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, class schedules, outlines, exercises, and tests for courses in beginning music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1961-1962. Theory I 56 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and exercises for a course in beginning music theory. Date(s) of materials: ? Theory I 1965-1966 56 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, lecture notes, outlines, exercises, and tests for a course in beginning music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1966. Theory I 1966 56 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and exercises for a course in beginning music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1966. Theory II 56 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and exercises for a course in intermediate music theory. Date(s) of materials: ? Theory II 1966-67 1966-1967 56 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, texts, lecture notes, outlines, and exercises for a course in intermediate music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1966-1967.
  - Theory (Box 157)
    Contents: Theory II 1965-66 1965-1966 57 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes, outlines, exercises, and tests for a course in intermediate music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1966. Theory III 57 1 item Contents: binder contains exercises for a course in intermediate music theory Date(s) of materials: ? Theory III 1966-67 I 1966-1967 57 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes, outlines, and exercises for a course in intermediate music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1966-1967. Theory IV [sic] 1980-1981 57 1 item Contents: binder contains correspondence, brochures, and other materials relating to di Bonaventura's service on a committee to design a degree in arts management. Date(s) of materials: 1980-1981. Theory Textbook 57 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied excerpts from an unattributed textbook on music theory. Date(s) of materials: ? Theory VI 1953-54 57 1 item Contents: binder contains exercises and lecture notes for a course in beginning music theory. Date(s) of materials: 1953-1954.
  - Theory, Vienna Wagner, Women (Box 158)
    Contents: Theory Workbook 58 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied pages from a music theory workbook and an unopened (shrink-wrapped) copy of Music in Theory and Practice: Solutions Manual to Volume I Workbook: Sixth Edition / Bruce Benward [and] Gary White. Date(s) of materials: ? Theory Workbook Volume I 58 1 item Contents: binder contains Instructor's Manual to Accompany Music in Theory and Practice: Fifth Edition: Volumes 1 and 2 / Bruce Benward [and] Gary White. Date(s) of materials: 1993? Theory Workbook Volume II 58 1 item Contents: binder contains Music in Theory and Practice: Solutions Manual to Accompany Workbook: Fourth Edition: Volume 1 / Bruce Benward [and] Gary White. Date(s) of materials: 1989? Vienna 58 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards bearing reproductions of artworks or photographs of historical Viennese personalities (including Beethoven and Schubert), architecture, and furnishings. Date(s) of materials: ? Wagner 58 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards, brochures, and clippings of images relating to Richard Wagner and his milieu. Date(s) of materials: ? Women 58 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards reproducing artwork by female painters. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Women in Music Medieval-Classical, [Survey of] World Music (Box 159)
    Contents: Women in Music Medieval-Classical 1997 59 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied book excerpts, and photocopied scores for a course in Women in Music. Date(s) of materials: 1997. Survey of World Music 1981-1993 59 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied book excerpts used in courses in folk, traditional, and world music. Date(s) of materials: 1981-1993. World Music Survey C-K 1986-1993 59 1 item Contents: binder contains primarily copies of handouts that supplemented oral reports by students in world music courses. Date(s) of materials: 1986-1993. Survey of World Music M-S 1986-1993 59 1 item Contents: binder contains primarily copies of handouts that supplemented oral reports by students in world music courses. Date(s) of materials: 1986-1993.